- [Lecturer] Now with a context object
and a component provider in place,
we want to manage the state
from one location only.
So the goal is to move the useReducer,
which for now is at the top level
of the app component.
We want to move it from here
to the context object,
inside the component provider.
Then we're going to move this as a value.
We're going to add this at the value
of the value prop.
So any descending components
of the component provider,
will have access to the global state.
That includes the state object
and the function dispatch.
We're going to do the same for
the initial state from line 15.
We're going to copy.
From line 15 to line 46.
And we're going to copy the initial state
and the function register.
And we're going to add this to the context,
like this.
So we are almost done.
We must make sure also that we add
useReducer to the scope,
of this module.
And we are good to go.
We're going to make a quick test.
So for now, we are not cutting
this from the app component.
We're going to make a quick test first,
to see how we can access and read the state
from the global state now.
With the context object.
So, I'm going to run with NPM start.
So let's open
the reactive tools.
And here you're going to see that
you have your context provider.
This value, which is the single prop.
Which is accepted in any component provider.
You have access to the state.
And also this function dispatch.
And in order to access it,
we're going to need to use another hook.
Coming next we make an introduction
to the use context.
Which is another hook,
that allows descending components
to consume the shared global state
from a function component.
So we're going to see how to use it.
Basically, it's going to accept
one context object as a parameter.
Then it's going to return a value
that corresponds to the global state.
And we're going to see how to use it.
I'm going to show you that next.
And actually you're going to see
how to use it with the challenge.